<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EngineerBetter</title><link>ileri.com/</link><description>Recent content on EngineerBetter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="ileri.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Product Thinking in Practice</title><link>ileri.com/blog/product-how/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/product-how/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve discussed the what and the why of a product thinking mindset. In this post, let&amp;rsquo;s explore the how, specifically how product thinking can be beneficial in some commonly experienced scenarios.
Who can benefit from Product Thinking? Product thinking can improve your ability to organise your strategy to goals, vet pain points, prioritise work to be done, and then also create less waste across your solutions. If you have a problem to be solved or desired business outcomes that you&amp;rsquo;re not certain how to organise thoughts &amp;amp; actions around, then chances are you could leverage product thinking frameworks.</description></item><item><title>CI Shootout: Conclusion</title><link>ileri.com/blog/ci-shootout-conclusion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/ci-shootout-conclusion/</guid><description>When should you use Jenkins, Concourse, Tekton or Argo Workflows? What work is each suited to, and what limitations do they each have? How will your choice of CI server affect the way that you work?
After comparing them on a variety of fronts, in this article we comment on how these systems differ and which you should use.
Recap You may wish to revisit some of the earlier posts to see the details about how each CI system compares:</description></item><item><title>Why is Product Thinking important?</title><link>ileri.com/blog/product-why/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/product-why/</guid><description>This post is the second in a series on Product Thinking:
What is a Product Thinking mindset? Product Thinking in practice EngineerBetter is known as a source of knowledge for helping back-end engineering teams deliver platform-based technology solutions to their consumers, i.e. product and delivery teams. What we&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years is that because these internal teams are often treated as support or supplemental functions, the same level of thought and care does not go into how they are positioned</description></item><item><title>What is a Product Thinking Mindset?</title><link>ileri.com/blog/product-thinking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/product-thinking/</guid><description>This post is the first in a series on Product Thinking:
Why is Product Thinking important? Product Thinking in practice Properly applied, agile and related approaches such as DevOps and CI/CD allow teams to build software faster. Product thinking is what allows us to deliver useful software. Our Managing Director Daniel Jones (known as Deejay) and I have had several chats around the potential benefits of leveraging a product thinking mindset in the work we do.</description></item><item><title>CI Shootout: Re-use and build monitors</title><link>ileri.com/blog/ci-shootout-reuse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/ci-shootout-reuse/</guid><description>In the previous blog we compared the act of reading state from, and writing state to, the outside world with four self-hosted CI systems: Jenkins, Concourse, Tekton &amp;amp; Argo Workflows. In this post we continue by looking at the re-usability of pipeline resources, and how well each serves as a build monitor.
First post - 1. Install and configure the CI system First post - 2. Run a &amp;ldquo;Hello, World&amp;rdquo; task Second post - 3.</description></item><item><title>Thought Reform</title><link>ileri.com/blog/thought-reform/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/thought-reform/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve previously written a blog post about strategies to effect mindset change, because EngineerBetter is in the business of helping organisations to perform cultural transformations. I feel a moral obligation to bring people&amp;rsquo;s attention to the malevolent side of mindset change. Just as I taught physical self-defence on a voluntary basis, I believe that it is important to raise awareness of intellectual self-defence.
Robert Jay Lifton identified eight criteria for thought reform - a somewhat euphemistic term used to less-sensationally describe what was feverishly reported as &amp;ldquo;brainwashing&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>CI Shootout: Triggering, Inputs, and Outputs</title><link>ileri.com/blog/ci-shootout-inputs-and-outputs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/ci-shootout-inputs-and-outputs/</guid><description>In the previous blog we looked at getting started with four self-hosted CI systems: Jenkins, Concourse, Tekton &amp;amp; Argo Workflows. In this post we continue by looking at the next set of use cases:
First post - 1. Install and configure the CI system First post - 2. Run a &amp;ldquo;Hello, World&amp;rdquo; task This post - 3. Trigger pipeline runs when external resources (eg Git repos, S3 buckets) change This post - 4.</description></item><item><title>CI Shootout: Getting started with Jenkins, Concourse, Tekton and Argo Workflows</title><link>ileri.com/blog/ci-shootout-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/ci-shootout-getting-started/</guid><description>At EngineerBetter we&amp;rsquo;ve evaluated four self-hosted CI systems in order to compare them against each other: Jenkins, Concourse, Tekton and Argo Workflows. For each CI system we&amp;rsquo;ve created some pipelines that:
Run pre-deployment static analysis over various forms of Infrastructure as Code Deploy a Kubernetes cluster to a staging environment Deploy the Sock Shop application to the cluster Run an acceptance test on the deployed application Promote the deployment by triggering an identical production pipeline Across a series of blog posts, we&amp;rsquo;ll be evaluating how each CI system supports the following use cases:</description></item><item><title>Migrating from Cloud Foundry to Kf</title><link>ileri.com/blog/migrating-to-kf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/migrating-to-kf/</guid><description>There is increasing demand amongst Cloud Foundry users to find a Kubernetes-based platform to run applications on. We recently compared some of the options to achieve this before settling on Google&amp;rsquo;s Kf for our own workloads.
To make it easier to move from Cloud Foundry to Kf, Google have added some features to the kf CLI for automating the migration of many Cloud Foundry resources. The kf CLI can now audit existing Cloud Foundry environments and move apps, spaces, service bindings and more between Cloud Foundry and a target Kf cluster.</description></item><item><title>We're Hiring - Building Better</title><link>ileri.com/blog/hiring-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/hiring-2021/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for people to join the EngineerBetter team on the next step of our journey to transform businesses to deliver useful software more quickly. We don&amp;rsquo;t want to do this for them, we want to do this with them. We are going to change the way that they implement their businesses through technology.
&amp;hellip;Useful software&amp;hellip; We need to build out our product management practice, both for our internal teams and to act as consultants and coaches to customers.</description></item><item><title>Concourse is Awesome</title><link>ileri.com/blog/concourse-is-awesome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/concourse-is-awesome/</guid><description>Concourse is a continuous thing do-er that happens to be rather good at CI/CD for big, complicated systems. At EngineerBetter we&amp;rsquo;re rather fond of it, and we wanted to explain why.
Concourse is &amp;lsquo;Pro&amp;rsquo; CI/CD Concourse is great for integrating lots of things, checking that they work together, and then progressing to something else like a release or promotion job. It has great fan-out, fan-in semantics.
Many folks have created Concourse-based &amp;lsquo;CI-as-a-Service&amp;rsquo; solutions at their organisations, building pipelined solutions so that app teams don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about writing their own.</description></item><item><title>EngineerBetter x Container Solutions</title><link>ileri.com/blog/engineerbetter-x-container-solutions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/engineerbetter-x-container-solutions/</guid><description>(Image via FizzyJinks. None of the fish in this story are as angry as the ones in that picture.)
EngineerBetter is now owned by Container Solutions. It won&amp;rsquo;t just be &amp;lsquo;business as usual&amp;rsquo;, it&amp;rsquo;ll be a case of &amp;lsquo;business even better&amp;rsquo;.
What&amp;rsquo;s staying the same? Much to the lament of my long-suffering team, I (Daniel Jones) will still be in charge of EngineerBetter, which will continue to operate as its own independent entity.</description></item><item><title>cf-for-k8s, KubeCF, Kf</title><link>ileri.com/blog/cf-for-k8s-kubecf-kf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/cf-for-k8s-kubecf-kf/</guid><description>There is no single obvious choice for those evaluating Kubernetes-based Cloud Foundry distributions and alternatives. Find out why EngineerBetter chose Google&amp;rsquo;s Kf for our estate, and why our advice to existing Cloud Foundry users is &amp;ldquo;stay on BOSH.&amp;rdquo;
In January VMware shut down their public Cloud Foundry (Pivotal Web Services). All of EngineerBetter&amp;rsquo;s apps ran on PWS and so we needed to migrate away from the platform and find something equally cheap and simple.</description></item><item><title>Engagement Deep-Dive: Continuous Everything in a Regulated Enterprise</title><link>ileri.com/blog/continuous-everything-regulated/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/continuous-everything-regulated/</guid><description>Over the last year EngineerBetter worked with Smarsh, introducing new ways of working that enabled continuous deployment of 19 data services and 20 apps across multiple vSphere environments in a regulated financial enterprise in 10 weeks - and that was just the start!
&amp;ldquo;We needed people to not just speak about the &amp;lsquo;right&amp;rsquo; thing or merely do it for others, we needed a team to partner with our engineers, model and teach the &amp;lsquo;right&amp;rsquo; thing so that it became pervasive organizationally.</description></item><item><title>Concourse Teams - Authentication and Automation</title><link>ileri.com/blog/concourse-auth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/concourse-auth/</guid><description>Configuring authentication providers in Concourse is often a source of confusion, with gotcha&amp;rsquo;s that make it easy for newcomers to remove their colleagues&amp;rsquo; access. In this post I explain how Concourse auth can be configured, and why I made concourse-mgmt to make the process more reliable.
Ever since version 2.0 Concourse has supported dividing a single Concourse installation into one or more teams. These teams can be configured so that only certain individuals can access the pipelines within them.</description></item><item><title>Quarks - a quickstart guide to deploying BOSH releases on K8s</title><link>ileri.com/blog/quarks-quickstart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/quarks-quickstart/</guid><description>Deploying BOSH releases to Kubernetes is entirely possible, but can be a little tricky to figure out from the documentation alone. This blog post fills in the gaps to provide a step-by-step guide for deploying a BOSH release on K8s with Quarks, deploying Redis as an example.
As the Cloud Foundry (CF) community moves towards the Kubernetes era of dominance, a few possible solutions for deploying CF on K8s have surfaced; one such solution is the Quarks/KubeCF combination.</description></item><item><title>Increasing Concourse worker container limits</title><link>ileri.com/blog/increasing-concourse-container-limits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/increasing-concourse-container-limits/</guid><description>Concourse runs all pipeline processes inside containers providing isolation, security and customisability. By default each Concourse worker allows only 250 containers to run concurrently, leading to the dreaded max containers reached error message. Thankfully this limit can be increased with two simple flags. How can you do this, should you do this, and why was the limit 250?
Hitting the limit Concourse/Garden is quite clear about what is happening when the container limit is reached, turning the job orange (the colour for &amp;ldquo;something within Concourse has failed&amp;rdquo;) and providing the error message max containers reached.</description></item><item><title>BYO Service Mesh to Cloud Foundry</title><link>ileri.com/blog/byo-service-mesh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/byo-service-mesh/</guid><description>Cloud Foundry has toyed around with the idea of providing service mesh capabilities to end users for a while. As CF transitions to a Kubernetes-based runtime, it looks like operators will soon be able to bring the full power of Istio &amp;amp; friends to their developers. But what if you aren&amp;rsquo;t an operator and you want all those features today?
Enter Hashicorp Consul. Consul offers service networking features such as health checking and service discovery whilst also bringing all the service mesh goodness of zero-trust networks, weighted traffic routing and circuit breaking.</description></item><item><title>BOSH-ception: Deploying a BOSH-lite Director on AWS</title><link>ileri.com/blog/bosh-lite-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/bosh-lite-on-aws/</guid><description>At EngineerBetter two things we love doing are writing tests and pipelining anything that moves. Recently when working with a client we found ourselves working on some custom BOSH releases. Naturally we started by creating a Concourse pipeline to create releases for us. I won&amp;rsquo;t go through the steps of the pipeline here but we have some examples of other release pipelines on GitHub.
As part of the TDD process we wanted to add some comprehensive system tests to our pipeline to help us resolve some issues that the client had been seeing with the release in the past.</description></item><item><title>SUSE Acquire Rancher Labs</title><link>ileri.com/blog/suse-acquire-rancher/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/suse-acquire-rancher/</guid><description>Yesterday SUSE announced that they are to acquire Rancher Labs, the folks who have helped thousands of customers deploy Kubernetes just about everywhere.
What it means for the market This makes for an interesting marketplace. We&amp;rsquo;ve got VMware, who went on a spending spree to give them everything they need for their Tanzu initiative. IBM bought Red Hat and with it Openshift, and now SUSE have undeniable Kubernetes credentials with the Rancher acquisition.</description></item><item><title>Deploying SUSE CaaS Platform on AWS</title><link>ileri.com/blog/suse-caasp-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/suse-caasp-on-aws/</guid><description>The SUSE Containers as a Service (CaaS) Platform deployment on AWS recently went into technological preview (as of version 4.1.2). I spent a few days going through the docs and deploying my own SUSE CaaS Platform (v4.2.1) on AWS, and here are my tips for a smooth deployment.
This blog post makes reference to &amp;ldquo;Master&amp;rdquo; nodes. This terminology is used only to maintain consistency with the official documentation.
What is SUSE CaaS Platform?</description></item><item><title>Cloud Foundry Rolling Deployments</title><link>ileri.com/blog/cloud-foundry-rolling-deployments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/cloud-foundry-rolling-deployments/</guid><description>Version 7 of Cloud Foundry&amp;rsquo;s cf CLI is now generally available. This makes rolling deployments a first-class feature, and adds many more flexible workflows than the original cf push offered. These changes bring the Cloud Foundry user experience more in line with what users have come to expected from Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; Deployments. Rolling deployments are now available - so why should you switch?
A History of cf push Over the last 18 months, the Cloud Controller (the brains of Cloud Foundry) has been extended to support a new set of APIs - collectively known as V3.</description></item><item><title>An Intro to the SUSE Cloud Application Platform Development Sandbox</title><link>ileri.com/blog/suse-cap-sandbox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/suse-cap-sandbox/</guid><description>Over the past couple of days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring the SUSE CAP Developer Sandbox, a free-of-charge playground version of SUSE Cloud Application Platform (CAP), built atop SUSE Cloud Foundry and Kubernetes.
Who&amp;rsquo;s it for? The SUSE CAP Sandbox is for any developer that wants to experiment, especially those that find their velocity is hindered by the processes of an enterprise engineering environment.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say, for example, you&amp;rsquo;re an engineer at a large bank.</description></item><item><title>EngineerBetter are Kubernetes Certified Service Providers</title><link>ileri.com/blog/engineerbetter-kubernetes-certified-service-providers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/engineerbetter-kubernetes-certified-service-providers/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to announce that EngineerBetter are now members of the Cloud Native Computing Foundation, and are Kubernetes Certified Service Providers. Combined with our partnerships with Google Cloud, IBM, (the company formerly known as) Pivotal, SUSE and VMware, this means we&amp;rsquo;re in a great position to help organisations be productive on Kubernetes, regardless of where they choose to use it. The message is simple - if you want to be more productive in the cloud, EngineerBetter can help.</description></item><item><title>Debugging Your Development Process</title><link>ileri.com/blog/debugging-your-development-process/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/debugging-your-development-process/</guid><description>By debugging your development process as well as your technology, you can deliver features into production more quickly, safely and often. By performance-tuning your organisation, you can be more productive without having to increase headcount. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll explain how you can debug your development process by using (or copying!) the Development Reality Check service that EngineerBetter offers, and how it can help you to achieve better outcomes.
EngineerBetter&amp;rsquo;s Development Reality Check can help you if you want to:</description></item><item><title>Transforming Minds and Organisations</title><link>ileri.com/blog/transforming-minds-and-organisations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/transforming-minds-and-organisations/</guid><description>All too often organisational transformations fail because leaders, technologists, consultants and agile coaches consider only part of the culture-change landscape. By using Harvard psychology professor Howard Gardner&amp;rsquo;s model of mindset change we can increase the chance of successful cultural change within individuals, teams and organisations. Whilst not a panacea or a &amp;lsquo;how to&amp;rsquo; guide, knowing and using the model can help leaders effect long-lasting change.
Cultural change is hard (thankfully - imagine the societal consequence if it was not).</description></item><item><title>Debugging Kubernetes Networking</title><link>ileri.com/blog/debugging-kubernetes-networking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/debugging-kubernetes-networking/</guid><description>At EngineerBetter, we&amp;rsquo;re going through the formality of ensuring that we&amp;rsquo;ve got the Certified Kubernetes Administrator qualification box ticked. Kelsey Hightower&amp;rsquo;s Kubernetes The Hard Way is a valuable guide to setting up a Kubes cluster &amp;lsquo;by hand&amp;rsquo;, and so I set about running through it.
All was going smoothly (well, after I realised that I&amp;rsquo;d screwed up the kubeconfig for kube-proxy, but that&amp;rsquo;s another story). By the end of the walkthrough I had three controller VMs running the api-server, etcd and scheduler, and three workers running kubelet and kube-proxy.</description></item><item><title>Why I'm saying farewell to EngineerBetter</title><link>ileri.com/blog/farewell-to-engineerbetter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/farewell-to-engineerbetter/</guid><description>What’s happening? This month I will be stepping down as CEO of EngineerBetter and leaving things in the capable hands of Daniel Jones, Ivana Scott and the rest of our amazing team of engineers. Over the coming months I’ll be working on new ideas, closer to where I live in Bristol. I’ll stay a close friend and partner of the company.
Wait, what? Yep. It’s true.
You may not have seen this one coming, so I&amp;rsquo;ve written down some reflections to help explain things a little better.</description></item><item><title>Kill The DevOps Team</title><link>ileri.com/blog/kill-the-devops-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/kill-the-devops-team/</guid><description>The DevOps Team must die.
The continued existence of The DevOps Team allows the misguided, the lazy and the dishonest to feign positive change under the covers of IT-meme buzzword compliance.
Inside a buzzword-compliant enterprise&amp;hellip; Are we agile? Check! We have sprints planned for the next three months! Do we have a Kubernetes strategy? Check! Apparently we need just one more month and then it&amp;rsquo;ll be in production. Are we DevOps?</description></item><item><title>kpack: another indicator Pivotal is bridging the CF/K8s gap</title><link>ileri.com/blog/kpack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/kpack/</guid><description>Pivotal recently announced the open-sourcing of kpack, a Kubernetes-native container build service, and non-commercial sibling of Pivotal Build Service. Essentially, kpack provides a &amp;lsquo;Kubernetes-native&amp;rsquo; means to automate the build and update of container images. It does this by providing Custom Resource Definitions (CRDs) as a user interface, these CRDs are then coordinated by Custom Resource Controllers (CRCs) to automate container image builds and keep them updated.
Where previously you might have introduced CI pipelines to watch for any Git or buildpack updates, now you can just point kpack at your Git repo and be done with it.</description></item><item><title>Hiring Golang Infrastructure Devs</title><link>ileri.com/blog/hiring-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/hiring-2019/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for people to join the EngineerBetter team.
Specifically we&amp;rsquo;re looking to hire for two streams of work, so we have two profiles we&amp;rsquo;re looking for:
Golang developers with Google Cloud infrastructure experience Platform engineers with prior experience of Concourse, CF, BOSH, Terraform, and ideally able to do TDD in Golang or Ruby Whilst we&amp;rsquo;ve got general background info on our Join Us page, this post will give a bit more detail about the streams of work we&amp;rsquo;re looking at.</description></item><item><title>Properly Promoting Pipelines</title><link>ileri.com/blog/pipeline-promotion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/pipeline-promotion/</guid><description>At EngineerBetter we spend a lot of time building Concourse pipelines to deploy complex systems such as Cloud Foundry. Here is an example of one of these pipelines:
It is simple, easy to understand, and it gets the job done. For most customers, however, the objective is rarely to deploy just one foundation. Usually there is a need for multiple deployments in multiple regions and possibly even on a multitude of IaaSes.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Infrastructure on Google Cloud</title><link>ileri.com/blog/continuous-infrastructure-google-cloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/continuous-infrastructure-google-cloud/</guid><description>Recently we helped the folks at Unit 2 Games automate the creation of their Google Cloud and Kubernetes infrastructure by using Concourse and EngineerBetter&amp;rsquo;s own best-practice approach to reliably deploying platforms.
&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve managed to take a huge step forward in our infrastructure automation with the help of EngineerBetter. Where our environments were once hand-crafted and fragile, they are now reliable, easy and flexible, and we&amp;rsquo;re getting really confident with the tooling they recommended.</description></item><item><title>Yubikeys for Signed Git Commits</title><link>ileri.com/blog/yubikey-signed-commits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/yubikey-signed-commits/</guid><description>By signing our Git commits, we can allow folks to verify that they were really written by the author tagged on the commit. If you&amp;rsquo;ve got a Yubikey set up as per our other blog posts, it&amp;rsquo;s a doddle to configure.
Ensure Public Key is on Keychain Your public key needs to be on your GPG installation&amp;rsquo;s keychain.
First, see if it is already on your chain (using your own address!</description></item><item><title>Migrating from Concourse-up to Control Tower</title><link>ileri.com/blog/migrating-to-control-tower/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/migrating-to-control-tower/</guid><description>Catch your connecting flight We recently announced that we are replacing Concourse-Up with Control Tower.
If you are currently running a Concourse using Concourse-up you might be wondering how to migrate over to Control Tower.
Under the hood Control Tower is Concourse-up with the name word-replaced and a handful of bugfixes/updates. Unfortunately due to some changes such as bucket name changes, deploying with Control Tower over top of Concourse-up will not work.</description></item><item><title>Concourse-Up becomes Control Tower</title><link>ileri.com/blog/concourse-up-renamed-to-control-tower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/concourse-up-renamed-to-control-tower/</guid><description>What happened? Concourse-Up has changed its name to Control Tower for Concourse. The repo and release naming has changed, along with all mention of concourse-up in the codebase, and the resources that Control Tower creates. In all other ways, Control Tower is the same thing as Concouse-Up.
Why have we done this? The main reason for doing this is the Concourse CI trademark guidelines. By meeting these guidelines, we now have more freedom over the direction we can take Control Tower as a product, including how we distribute or commercialise it in the future.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Concourse-Up for GCP</title><link>ileri.com/blog/concourse-up-gcp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/concourse-up-gcp/</guid><description>Going Multi-Cloud In 2017 we announced Concourse-Up - the fastest way to go from nothing to a fully working production Concourse CI, using just a single command.
Since then, we added a lot of operational features to help folks spend as little time as possible thinking about CI administration. This includes the ability for a Concourse-Up deployment to automatically upgrade itself when new versions of Concourse-Up are released, keeping you up to date with Concourse and all the components (UAA, Credhub, Grafana, etc).</description></item><item><title>PKS - a Painkiller for Kubernetes</title><link>ileri.com/blog/pks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/pks/</guid><description>PKS is Pivotal&amp;rsquo;s Kubernetes distribution that brings self-service Kubernetes-as-a-Service to the enterprise, be that on private or public cloud. By leveraging the BOSH deployment tool under the hood, PKS is able to solve many of the most common headaches for Kubernetes operators.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with PKS (Pivotal Kubernetes Container Service), standing it up on a variety of IaaSes, and keeping it up-to-date using Concourse pipelines - just as we do with Cloud Foundry.</description></item><item><title>Current Reality Trees to Lift the Fog of War</title><link>ileri.com/blog/current-reality-trees-fog-of-war/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/current-reality-trees-fog-of-war/</guid><description>EngineerBetter was asked to engage with a major utility company. Their software delivery operation, comprising approximately 600 developers, was underpinned by a single platform team that was responsible for deployments and for moving the organisation towards a continuous delivery mode of operation.
The platform team was dysfunctional, preventing deployments (including critical security fixes) from going live. This was receiving understandable attention from senior executives.
Simply observing the team during meetings revealed a number of symptoms:</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes for CF Users Course</title><link>ileri.com/blog/kubernetes-for-cf-users-course/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/kubernetes-for-cf-users-course/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll be teaching a Kubernetes for CF Users course at this year&amp;rsquo;s Cloud Foundry Summit Europe, in collaboration with the fine folks at SUSE.
The course, developed by EngineerBetter, is written for Cloud Foundry users and decision-makers. It explores Kubernetes through the lens of Cloud Foundry, giving students hands-on experience of all the Kubernetes equivalents of common Cloud Foundry tasks. We take students through the differences and commonalities between the two platforms, identifying the use cases to which each is most suited.</description></item><item><title>Concourse-Up Manifest for beginners</title><link>ileri.com/blog/concourse_up_manifest_beginners/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/concourse_up_manifest_beginners/</guid><description>Concourse-Up was born in May 2017 and is a project that keeps on being nurtured by our team. We&amp;rsquo;re proud to make a difference to our users working on a tool that makes their lives easier, because life is too short for worrying about your Concourse deployments!
To understand Concourse-Up, it is important to acknowledge the value of the Concourse-Up manifest, which is how we describe the exact combination of components that Concourse-Up deploys.</description></item><item><title>Improving Concourse Performance</title><link>ileri.com/blog/improving-concourse-performance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/improving-concourse-performance/</guid><description>Since introducing CredHub into the concourse-up distribution, we became aware of some performance issues with it. We noticed if you had lots of resouces, the load on the ATC would be very high, and the system would feel very sluggish.
In concourse-up we colocate the Concourse ATC, CredHub, UAA, and some other components on the web VM. We tried scaling this VM to be a larger instance type but saw little to no improvement.</description></item><item><title>Escaping the Iron Triangle</title><link>ileri.com/blog/escaping-iron-triangle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/escaping-iron-triangle/</guid><description>Through use of Value Stream Mapping, Impact Mapping and Cost of Delay we&amp;rsquo;ve helped IT leadership teams to break out of the iron triangle of traditional project management thinking. Instead they&amp;rsquo;ve been able to understand their organisation as a system, get visibility of things that really matter and find new ways to set direction, prioritise and measure progress.
A familiar story If you’ve worked in any organisation where the number of employees is measured in thousands you&amp;rsquo;ve probably experienced some common behavioural patterns and frustrations.</description></item><item><title>Receiving Feedback</title><link>ileri.com/blog/receiving-feedback/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/receiving-feedback/</guid><description>People aren&amp;rsquo;t scared of failure - they&amp;rsquo;re scared of criticism. Defensiveness increases the transaction costs of getting even the simplest problem solved. If we can better equip people to receive feedback, then we can remove a major source of lost productivity and lost potential.
At EngineerBetter we have a Git repo of documentation to provoke thought about whether we&amp;rsquo;re doing the best we can. This blog post is an expansion of one of the docs in that repo.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Foundry + Kubernetes is Positive-Sum</title><link>ileri.com/blog/cf-kube-positive-sum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/cf-kube-positive-sum/</guid><description>Cloud Foundry&amp;rsquo;s sweet spot has always been making stateless twelve-factor apps as easy to deploy as they should be. This functionality is as needed now as it&amp;rsquo;s ever been - if not more so.
There is a huge potential to bring the benefits of Cloud Foundry to those folks handcrafting their own platforms on Kubernetes, saving them vast amounts of time and money as a result. As Cloud Foundry&amp;rsquo;s dear friend Sam Ramji would likely say: this is a positive-sum game.</description></item><item><title>Yubikey All The Things</title><link>ileri.com/blog/yubikey-all-the-things/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/yubikey-all-the-things/</guid><description>Paddy Steed is one of the newer members of EngineerBetter, and has a keen eye for all things related to security and cryptography. Soon after joining us he outlined a great way for us to securely use shared machines whilst pairing.
Each team member now has a single Yubikey USB security device that does all of the following:
Stores and loads our personal SSH keys Provides one-touch two-factor authentication Stores and recalls our 1Password secret keys Allows Git commits to be signed, proving the author&amp;rsquo;s identity SSH After a little setup, an engineer inserts their Yubikey, enters a PIN, and then their SSH key is loaded all the time the device is connected.</description></item><item><title>Yubikeys for SSH Auth</title><link>ileri.com/blog/yubikey-ssh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/yubikey-ssh/</guid><description>You can use a Yubikey USB device to securely generate and store your SSH key. This can be used to load your private key on demand, protected by a PIN. Perfect for pair-programming on shared machines!
In this post I will show you how to use your Yubikey to generate and store an RSA key, and then configure your computer to use GPG to load that key and authenticate with remote SSH servers.</description></item><item><title>Yubikeys for Static Secrets</title><link>ileri.com/blog/yubikey-static-secret/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/yubikey-static-secret/</guid><description>You can use your Yubikey to remember and type an arbitrary string, as well as using it as a OTP generator and a secure store for your SSH key. We use this so that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to remember our 1Password secret keys.
We use 1Password as our team secrets-management tool. It&amp;rsquo;s great, but every user needs to remember not only their username and password, but a 40-character secret key too.</description></item><item><title>Yubikeys for Two-Factor Auth</title><link>ileri.com/blog/yubikey-2fa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/yubikey-2fa/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re amassing a plethora of user accounts that require two-factor authentication (2FA) and let&amp;rsquo;s face it, you should, then you&amp;rsquo;ll be pleased to learn how you can use a USB Yubikey to avoid having to type in as many one-time-passwords (OTPs).
Two-Factor Authentication with One-Time Passwords Traditional OTPs protect against password reuse, weak passwords and credential leakage.
A user&amp;rsquo;s login procedure using a traditional OTP is usually something like this:</description></item><item><title>Deploying Kubernetes with BOSH</title><link>ileri.com/blog/kubernetes-with-bosh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/kubernetes-with-bosh/</guid><description>As the popularity of containerization continues to rise, so too has the use of services like Kubernetes, which automate deployment, scaling and management of applications by development teams. But what happens when a core component of your Kubernetes cluster suddenly fails?
In a traditional scenario, the death of a sickly Kubernetes node would have to be brought to the attention of a platform operator, who would then have to follow a number of manual (and not always fully documented) steps to bring it back to life.</description></item><item><title>Post-DevOps - A Definition</title><link>ileri.com/blog/post-devops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/post-devops/</guid><description>&lt;p>Post-DevOps describes a level of &lt;strong>maturity&lt;/strong> that achieves &lt;strong>agility beyond traditional DevOps&lt;/strong> by a &lt;strong>platform product team&lt;/strong> providing a self-service, automatable platform which enables application product teams to perform all operational activities. Traditional &lt;strong>DevOps is still practiced&lt;/strong> by both application product teams and the platform product team, above and below the &amp;lsquo;platform line&amp;rsquo; respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bringing Perpetual Motion to System Upgrades - Self-Upgrading Concourse CI</title><link>ileri.com/blog/perpetual-motion-software-updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/perpetual-motion-software-updates/</guid><description>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve recently been working on adding functionality to &lt;a href="https://github.com/EngineerBetter/concourse-up">Concourse-Up&lt;/a>, based on feedback from users in the community and our own teams who&amp;rsquo;ve been using it in production with customers. Being able to deploy a Concourse cluster using a single command was great, but not ideal; you still had to run it again to upgrade. What if you could just run a single command, and then &lt;em>never have to think about it again&lt;/em>? In pursuit of this goal, we added a self-update feature.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intensive, Immersive Training with Mob Programming</title><link>ileri.com/blog/immersive-intensive-training/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/immersive-intensive-training/</guid><description>&lt;p>EngineerBetter recently had the pleasure of delivering a novel training course that &lt;strong>bridges the gap between&lt;/strong> the one-to-one mentoring of &lt;strong>pair-programming&lt;/strong>, and the more scalable one-to-many knowledge transfer of an &lt;strong>instructor-led training&lt;/strong> course.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="challenge">Challenge&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Take 6 factory engineers from a global manufacturer with some experience of assembly, C, C# and Visual Basic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In &lt;strong>only five days&lt;/strong> have them deliver &lt;strong>12-Factor&lt;/strong> apps written in Java Spring Boot/JavaScript Node that ingest, store and visualise &lt;strong>IoT data&lt;/strong>, and is under &lt;strong>version control&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>test-driven&lt;/strong>, built using &lt;strong>BDD&lt;/strong> stories, and &lt;strong>continuously deployed&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>Cloud Foundry&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The above are all things the &lt;strong>developers had never done before&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Achieve the above with only two folks from EngineerBetter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Did our students achieve their goal? Of course! So how did we help them do it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Concentric Rings of the Cloud-Native Enterprise</title><link>ileri.com/blog/rings-cloud-native/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/rings-cloud-native/</guid><description>&lt;p>At EngineerBetter we generally categorise cloud-native transformation challenges into four problem spaces:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Self-Service Platforms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Continuous Delivery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Application Architecture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Organisational Change&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Through our experiences with enterprises, we began to arrange these problem spaces into a mental model formed of concentric rings. We&amp;rsquo;ve found it useful to structure our thinking like this when we talk to customers, because it helps highlight how platform adoption tends to reveal new problems and constraints, in an ever wider context.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Anthropic Sympathy of Platforms</title><link>ileri.com/blog/anthropic-sympathy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/anthropic-sympathy/</guid><description>&lt;p>The way &lt;strong>most enterprises&lt;/strong> operate is &lt;strong>wasting both the time and money&lt;/strong> that they are made from. By learning from cognitive psychology and neuroscience we can find better, more productive ways of working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The commonly-accepted working practices of today are born of the industrial revolution and the post-war era of mass production. It&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that these methods are best suited to &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->paperwork factories&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> and not the creative endeavour of solving business problems with software.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Introducing Concourse-Up - Deploy Concourse CI in a Single Command</title><link>ileri.com/blog/introducing-concourse-up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/introducing-concourse-up/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that we love &lt;a href="https://concourse.ci">Concourse&lt;/a>. Concourse is a new kind of continuous integration server that treats pipelines as a first class citizen. It uses declarative config and a minimal UI to ensure that your builds can always be repeated, and your CI server always recoverable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Concourse is notoriously easy to get started with, but as soon as you want your team to use it in production you&amp;rsquo;ve previously had to learn &lt;a href="https://bosh.io">BOSH&lt;/a> (which is notoriously hard to get started with). Teams who just want great CI shouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to think about this, so we built a tool called &lt;a href="https://github.com/engineerbetter/concourse-up">Concourse-Up&lt;/a> to get your cluster up and keep it running, using a single command.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Foundry Certified Developer Training at CF Summit</title><link>ileri.com/blog/cfcd-summit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/cfcd-summit/</guid><description>&lt;p>EngineerBetter are teaming up with &lt;a href="https://rscale.io/">Resilient Scale&lt;/a> to deliver the &lt;strong>full three-day&lt;/strong> Cloud Foundry Certified Developer training course in the &lt;strong>days before the Cloud Foundry Silicon Valley Summit 2017&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>$1,975 for all three days&lt;/strong> with &lt;strong>lunch&lt;/strong> provided. The course is held at the Santa Clara Convention Center, which is conveniently the &lt;strong>same location as CF Summit&lt;/strong>. &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/cloud-foundry-for-developers-cf-summit-tickets-33932914260">You can &lt;strong>enrol via Eventbrite&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;ll be a packed few days, full of &lt;strong>hands-on practical exercises&lt;/strong>, interactive walk-throughs, and &lt;strong>surprisingly few slides&lt;/strong>. The course is &lt;strong>programming-language agnostic&lt;/strong>, and students also get the pick the brains of &lt;strong>two highly-experienced Cloud Foundry consultants&lt;/strong> - &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sgreenberg/">Steve Greenberg&lt;/a> and I.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High Performance Ops for Enterprise PaaS</title><link>ileri.com/blog/high-performance-ops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/high-performance-ops/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last month I spoke at the excellent &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/London-Continuous-Delivery/">London Continuous Delivery&lt;/a> meetup about how EngineerBetter have recently been helping one of our financial services customers &lt;a href="ileri.com/2016/12/14/continuously-deploying-pivotal-cloudfoundry.html">continuously deploy Cloud Foundry&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is just the beginning of a process of continuous improvement, but already we have seen the magic that can happen when you start working in small batch sizes and begin to organise Enterprise IT teams around a &amp;lsquo;platform as a product&amp;rsquo; mindset.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Continuously Deploying Pivotal Cloud Foundry</title><link>ileri.com/blog/continuously-deploying-pivotal-cloudfoundry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/continuously-deploying-pivotal-cloudfoundry/</guid><description>&lt;p>EngineerBetter recently helped a large financial organisation &lt;strong>fully automate&lt;/strong> their Pivotal Cloud Foundry deployments, taking a manual process that took a whole team more than a week, and replacing it with an &lt;strong>hands-off&lt;/strong> continuous depoyment pipeline that &lt;strong>took mere hours&lt;/strong>, often &lt;strong>overnight whilst the team slept&lt;/strong>. We didn&amp;rsquo;t just automate the deployment of their PCF: we &lt;strong>automated&lt;/strong> the creation of their &lt;strong>cloud infrastructure&lt;/strong>; deployment of &lt;strong>upgrades&lt;/strong>; installation of &lt;strong>security updates&lt;/strong>; and all with &lt;strong>full testing&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cloud Foundry enables continuous delivery for developers. &lt;strong>EngineerBetter bring continuous delivery to platform operators&lt;/strong> and traditional IT teams. Here&amp;rsquo;s how.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Concourse Container Leak</title><link>ileri.com/blog/concourse-container-leaks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/concourse-container-leaks/</guid><description>&lt;p>A customer of ours recently had trouble with their Concourse instance which resulted in us raising a &lt;a href="https://github.com/concourse/baggageclaim/issues/6">GitHub issue&lt;/a> describing how containers may get orphaned and that users may experience the error message &lt;code>insufficient subnets remaining in the pool&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can mostly easily be remedied by performing &lt;code>bosh recreate&lt;/code> on the Worker VM, or if you&amp;rsquo;re not sensible enough to have deployed your Concourse with BOSH, by locating and killing all the orphaned container processes. The debugging journey was rather fun and exposed some of the innards of Concourse and Garden, so we&amp;rsquo;ve decided to share it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pipelining Platforms, just like Apps</title><link>ileri.com/blog/pipelining-platforms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/pipelining-platforms/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re responsible for operating shared IT services in a global enterprise, providing a self-service platform to your internal developers. If you were to continuously deliver this platform, in exactly the same way as cloud native apps themselves, what would it mean to your teams and your business?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Firstly, try to imagine a shared IT platform in a global company where its suddenly economical to work in small batch sizes, allowing you to actually embrace change rather than resist it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EngineerBetter become Hazelcast Partners</title><link>ileri.com/blog/engineerbetter-hazelcast-cloud-foundry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/engineerbetter-hazelcast-cloud-foundry/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://hazelcast.com/partners/systems-integrators/">EngineerBetter is now a systems integration partner of Hazelcast, Inc.&lt;/a>, specialising in helping people leverage the Hazelcast in-memory data-grid alongside their Cloud Foundry deployments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re the only Hazelcast SI partner who are also &lt;a href="https://www.cloudfoundry.org/membership/members/">Cloud Foundry Foundation members&lt;/a>, making EngineerBetter the go-to consultancy for integrating the two technologies&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EngineerBetter Join the Cloud Foundry Foundation</title><link>ileri.com/blog/engineerbetter-cloud-foundry-foundation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/engineerbetter-cloud-foundry-foundation/</guid><description>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re very pleased to announce that EngineerBetter Ltd is now a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->silver member&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> of the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Cloud Foundry Foundation&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>EngineerBetter is the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->only UK-native consultancy&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> that is a member of the Cloud Foundry Foundation. We&amp;rsquo;re also independent, with no vested interest in selling you one distribution or another.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hiring</title><link>ileri.com/blog/hiring/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/hiring/</guid><description>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re looking for people to &lt;strong>join the EngineerBetter team&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whilst we&amp;rsquo;ve given as succinct a write-up as possible on our &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Join Us&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> page, we decided to write this blog post to give as much background and context as possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brain-Aligned Delivery Notes</title><link>ileri.com/blog/brain-aligned-delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/brain-aligned-delivery/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m giving a talk entitled &lt;a href="http://sparkthechange.co.uk/sessions/brain-aligned-delivery/">Brain-Aligned Delivery&lt;/a> at &lt;a href="http://sparkthechange.co.uk/">Spark The Change&lt;/a>. The presentation is an aggregration of various cognitive psychology and neuroscience findings that apply to working practices, and this post serves as accompanying notes, with links to its many &lt;strong>references&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Up and running with BOSH and Concourse - Part 2</title><link>ileri.com/blog/bosh-concourse2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/bosh-concourse2/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="ileri.com/bosh-concourse.html">Part 1&lt;/a> of this tutorial we set up a new BOSH director from scratch on AWS. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to deploy Concourse!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-will-we-do-next">What will we do next?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create a deployment manifest for Concourse&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upload stemcells and releases, then deploy using BOSH&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Install and get started with the fly cli&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Try a more complex deployment&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Up and running with BOSH and Concourse - Part 1</title><link>ileri.com/blog/bosh-concourse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/bosh-concourse/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Cloud Foundry ecosystem has given rise to some amazing things. This series of posts is about two of them - BOSH and Concourse. Together with CF, they form an awesome triangle of tools that will change the way you think about how to get things done when delivering software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BOSH is the distributed systems powerhouse that makes Cloud Foundry possible. It answers the impossible question: How do you continuously deliver not just an app, but &lt;em>an entire platform&lt;/em> of distributed virtual infrastructure?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Concourse is a intuitive, cloud-native CI tool that has a powerful simplicity to it. Actually, I&amp;rsquo;d go so far as to say it&amp;rsquo;s more than just an automation tool, it&amp;rsquo;s a medium for artistic expression! Just have a look at some of the vast Pivotal pipelines (e.g. &lt;a href="https://buildpacks.ci.cf-app.com/">the Buildpacks team&lt;/a>) and marvel at their aesthetic value.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Why, How and What of EngineerBetter</title><link>ileri.com/blog/why-engineerbetter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/why-engineerbetter/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="_why_-does-engineerbetter-exist">&lt;em>Why&lt;/em> does EngineerBetter exist?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We started this company to make things better for people who build software for a living. This includes both our customers and our employees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>EngineerBetter was founded in the belief that today&amp;rsquo;s status quo is not good enough for humans. We think there should be less friction in the way we work. We should be more effective and we should learn quicker.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Foundry Summit Berlin</title><link>ileri.com/blog/cf-summit-berlin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/cf-summit-berlin/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m talking at &lt;a href="http://berlin2015.cfsummit.com/">Cloud Foundry Summit Berlin 2015&lt;/a> - please do feel free to stop me for a chat!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m giving a presentation called &lt;a href="http://cfsummiteu2015.sched.org/event/41eac05623fff1f608972a6b5dde4bfe">The Seven Stages Of Bosh&lt;/a>, along with my good pal &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cghsystems">Chris Hedley&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.cloudcredo.com">CloudCredo&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s Director of Engineering.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overflowing buildpack_cache</title><link>ileri.com/blog/overflowing-buildpack_cache/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/overflowing-buildpack_cache/</guid><description>&lt;p>Between versions 206 and 211 of Cloud Foundry a bug causes &lt;code>buildpack_cache&lt;/code> files to be orphaned, increasing persistent disk usage unless manual remedial action is taken.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users will get the error message &lt;code>Staging error: cannot get instances since staging failed&lt;/code> when trying to push or restage apps. Depending on your setup you could get higher AWS S3 bills, or you may run out of persistent disk on your Cloud Controller or NFS Server VMs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Flood of Droplets</title><link>ileri.com/blog/a-flood-of-droplets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/a-flood-of-droplets/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you play the dangerous game of scaling Cloud Foundry DEAs up instead of out, make sure you have plenty of headroom in the CPU department to start with. If you don&amp;rsquo;t then there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance you&amp;rsquo;ll see a heap of &lt;code>no available stagers&lt;/code> errors upon &lt;code>cf push&lt;/code> and &lt;code>insufficient resources to start&lt;/code> errors upon &lt;code>cf start&lt;/code>. This will last for an hour before magically fixing itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why is this? What causes all these errors, and what can be done if one gets it wrong?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenJDK 1.8.0_u40 Kerberos MS Auth Bug</title><link>ileri.com/blog/openjdk-kerberos-bug/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/openjdk-kerberos-bug/</guid><description>&lt;p>I discovered an &lt;a href="https://bugs.openjdk.java.net/browse/JDK-8078439">OpenJDK 1.8.0_u40 bug&lt;/a> whereby only the first OID in a Kerberos ticket will be considered for supportability; if your server can only authenticate using mechanisms further down the OID list in the ticket then you&amp;rsquo;re bang out of luck.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Foundry Summit 2015 Themes</title><link>ileri.com/blog/cf-summit-2015-themes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/blog/cf-summit-2015-themes/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m back from the excellent &lt;a href="http://cfsummit.com">Cloud Foundry Summit 2015&lt;/a>, and have been back in the country long enough to catch up on some sleep. That picture up there is the poolside area where I may have sipped a few pints of Californian IPA between presentations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were plenty of interesting talks about specific subjects (CC V3 API, Service Broker API updates), but I wanted to recount some common topics that cropped up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About us</title><link>ileri.com/about-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/about-us/</guid><description>Our values &amp;#9830;Make things better Organisations’ investment and the time of their staff are both very valuable. Don’t repeat past mistakes, accept inefficiencies, or hold back change.
&amp;#9830;Seek opportunities to learn World-changing technologies and businesses don’t look like those of five years ago. We stay cutting edge via a range of learning strategies.
&amp;#9830;Don’t do overtime or ‘crunch’ We do our best work, all day. Overtime and deadline ‘crunch’ hide information about the reality of the project from the people who need to see it.</description></item><item><title>Concourse Training</title><link>ileri.com/concourse-training/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/concourse-training/</guid><description>Instructor-led Concourse training Our exclusive one-day course covers everything beginners need to become proficient in building production systems using Concourse, delivered live by expert practitioners who use Concourse on a daily basis.
&amp;#xe901; On-site, or online via Zoom &amp;#xe901; Hands-on exercises &amp;#xe901; Local training environment provided &amp;#xe901; Interactive recap sessions The extremely hands-on course guides students to author a re-usable pipeline that compiles and tests code, accesses secrets securely and features role-based access control.</description></item><item><title>Hosted Concourse</title><link>ileri.com/hosted-concourse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/hosted-concourse/</guid><description>Concourse-as-a-Service All of Concourse, none of the hassle Hosted Concourse allows you to build your systems using all the power that Concourse pipelines provide, but without the expense and effort of running the infrastructure. Our hosted Concourse service is currently in an invite-only private beta. Register your interest and we'll let you know when we're ready on onboard more users. Get in touch See how much we can help you.</description></item><item><title>How we work</title><link>ileri.com/how-we-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/how-we-work/</guid><description>Helping your business
cope with change We'll help you make sense of transformation in your organisation, and show you the huge potential of working in a way that embraces change, rather than rejecting it. Our approach breaks down into three key areas:
&amp;#xe901;&amp;nbsp;1&amp;nbsp;&amp;#xe901; Help development or
operations teams be
more effective
&amp;#xe901;&amp;nbsp;2&amp;nbsp;&amp;#xe901; Help management or
project leaders have
their needs met
without conflict
&amp;#xe901;&amp;nbsp;3&amp;nbsp;&amp;#xe901; Coach executive
leaders in an</description></item><item><title>Join our team</title><link>ileri.com/join-our-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/join-our-team/</guid><description>What we offer Between £35-100k for permanent employees: from newbies, to experienced developers, to team leaders who can consult with clients. Workplace Pension Private Medical Insurance and Dental Cover with Bupa Cycle to Work Scheme Nice, inclusive people. We pair-program a lot so we all have to get along well. A team built on trust and transparency, where what you believe is more important than what you know. Interesting and rewarding work, with customers ranging from global brands to software startups.</description></item><item><title>Our services</title><link>ileri.com/our-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/our-services/</guid><description>Instructor-led training We deliver these hands-on, on-site, instructor-led courses:
&amp;#xe901; 4 day CF Certified Developer &amp;#xe901; 1 day CF Zero To Hero &amp;#xe901; 1 day Concourse Basics EngineerBetter authored the official CF Certified Developer training programme, delivered the Zero To Hero course at CF Summit Europe, as well as to many direct customers.
Days
Immersive training A novel training course bridging the gap between one-to-one mentoring of pair-programming, and more scalable one-to-many knowledge transfer of instructor-led training.</description></item><item><title>Success Stories</title><link>ileri.com/success-stories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/success-stories/</guid><description>Some of our clients Delivering 5x the software with 15% of the ops effort are typical results for these folks. When they talked about their infrastructure upgrading itself overnight while everyone was asleep, I said 'I've been on a 22 year quest to make what you just said happen.' Tony HansmannDirector of Cloud Ops, Pivotal
Get in touch See how much we can help you.
Call +44 (0) 20 7846 0140 or</description></item><item><title>Why Cloud-Native?</title><link>ileri.com/why-cloud-native/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>ileri.com/why-cloud-native/</guid><description>Our technology Kubernetes Kubernetes is the world's most popular container orchestration tool, used for deploying distributed systems and building higher order cloud platforms. We offer training and expertise in K8S, helping teams with the most effective ways of working to ensure highly robust, testable and reproducible deployments. Cloud Foundry Cloud Foundry is an enterprise development platform allowing the fastest route from code to feedback, while maximising portability across clouds. We help enterprises with good practices for operating Cloud Foundry, allowing them to focus on their applications.</description></item></channel></rss>